#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Freelance Software Engineer at self-employed (Jun 2019 - Present)

- Built rich SPAs using Vue/Nuxt, React, Angular.
- Developed with serverless Node.js and JavaScript
- Built RESTful APIs using a serverless framework
- Developed architectures on top of AWS Lambda, AWS CloudFormation, and AWS S3
- Collaborated with other developers in an Agile environment, using Scrum methodology

Technologies : Vue.js, Nuxt.js, React, Angular, AWS, Docker, Node.js, Serverless, Microservices

### React Engineer at StrongBlock (Nov 2018 - May 2019)

- Built and maintained development, staging, and production infrastructure on AWS
- Built a rich SPA using React
- Personally supervised and trained a team of 2 front-end interns
- Deployed the application in Docker containers using a DigitalOcean droplet

Technologies: React, AWS, Docker, Linux, Git, DigitalOcean

### React/RoR Engineer at MAZ Systems Inc (Mar 2017 - Nov 2018)

- Developed a progressive static web app with responsive UI components
- Integrated the site with headless CMS and implemented GraphQL queries to retrieve data
- Deployed the site in Netlify. Configured a custom domain and SSL certification
- Bought domain at Namecheap and configured DNS records to point to Netlify name servers
- Configured Google's reCaptcha and built contact form using Formik

Technologies : React, TailwindCSS, Ruby on Rails, Google Analytics, GraphQL



Jimmy Yu Web Technologies Expert

jimmyyu0207@gmail.com (717) 287-5835

#### **SUMMARY**

First and foremost, I love writing code. Ever since writing my first program in JavaScript manipulating it to produce a desired output, I've obsessed with the idea of using software to solve practical problems. Software engineering is a never ending puzzle that I'm passionately engaged in solving. I power of believe the programming to transform and improve the lives of people around the world.

For my first professional contract, I was given the opportunity to lead a full UI/UX overhaul start up's website using React. This contract quickly turned into a full time offer and I have happily expanded my role as a software engineer.

I've been working as a senior web technologies expert for 7 years and built many websites & web apps for various industries.

Through Development, I could get the good understanding of several industries like social media, healthcare, real estate, construction, finance service, etc.

# Vue Engineer at Design Everest (Jun 2016 - Feb 2017)

- Started as lead UI/UX developer and advanced to team lead and project manager
- Built rich SPAs using Vue/Nuxt, Angular
- Coached other team members on process improvement, task completion, and technical challenges
- Drove the process improvement efforts associated with the development team's agile transformation

Technologies: Vue.js, Nuxt.js, Angular, Linux, Docker, Git

## Angular Engineer at Mesosphere (Feb 2013 - Jun 2016)

- Modernized the front-end on a legacy system to enable responsive layouts and mobile views
- Enhanced the billing system by implementing several payment gateway integrations
- Carried out the full E2E test infrastructure
- Implemented multiple integrations with third parties
- Built multiple CRUD operations, authorization, logging, and more
- Designed and developed new data visualizations, infographics, and interfaces for an enterprise Al/IoT application using HighCharts and D3.js

Technologies : AngularJs, Angular, HighCharts, D3.js, jQuery, Git, Google Map API

#### **EDUCATION**

The Hong Kong University of Science and Technology (2007 > 2011)

Bachelor's degree of Computer Science

### **SKILLS**

JavaScript (7 yrs) HTML/HTML5 (7 yrs) CSS/CSS3 (7 yrs) React (5 yrs)

Vue.js (4 yrs) Angular (5 yrs)

Node.js (4 yrs)

Express (4 yrs)

Python/Django (2 yrs)

PHP/Laravel (2 yrs)

Ruby on Rails (2 yrs)

MongoDB (2 yrs)

PostgreSQL (2 yrs)

MySQL (6 yrs)

Amazon Web Services (2 yrs)

Google Cloud Platform (3 yrs)

Docker (4 yrs)